Hello, all my friends, and welcome to exercise number 33.
So write a program to reverse Nora.
It's very common question in all the universities and other interviews in big companies that may ask
you to reverse an array.
So what is an algorithm or an algorithm to reverse an array?
Host the video and think about it.
Write them down in your copy book after we solve it.
And please write your solution in the comments below.
In order to discuss if you have any points to be made to clarify.
So first of all, I need to create that air raid that we are going to, that we get to reverse.
It's my array here.
Vehicle two, I want to reverse like 11 20 to 30 three four four five five six six seven seven eight
eight.
OK.
This is their raid that I go into reverse.
OK?
OK, now
we will start by reversing or reversing, using the loop, so we start and equal to zero I less than
every my age dot length.
Over two, because we are reversing and I need to go to the half of the array and the start like switching
them elements of the first, the first element at the to at index zero would be the last element at
index my rate at length.
This is their algorithm, so I don't need to reverse that.
The next half of the other half, I need to reverse only the first half of that array because I would
create every time I loop, I will create a temporary and variable called temp, and I will get it from
my era at index.
I my array at index I.
Equal to or in the yes, that's equal to my array, my array at index, my entry, the claim minus a
minus one, I will show you in the demonstration next couple of minutes how this what does this mean
now reversing my array dot length minus I minus one.
Is equal to them.
OK.
Therefore.
If we get from the loop, we exit from the loop here system that out duct brain alarm and reverse everyday.
Arrays dot to a string.
And I need to print array the reverse there.
OK, so let's run and see.
And here we go, we our app, our application and program is working fine.
We have reversed the a eight eight seven seven six six, and so now let's go deeply in the reversing
the Loop algorithm.
OK, so.
Let me make this and here.
We start by 11, 11, 12, 22, three three four four five five six, six seven seven and eight eight.
We start, we go through the loop from the first and it tells the length over two.
So what is the length of this?
It is eight.
So the half of this array is this number.
OK, so this the first part.
It is 11, 22, 33 and 44.
OK, and the other part and the next part or the other part is five five six six seven seven eight eight.
We start every time by creating a temporary integer variable called them and assigning every time temporary
at the first iteration as 11.
Now, Miri and I equal my array of the other side minus I minus one.
OK, so this is the first this is the first segment.
It's the first part.
And the other part of the second part is five five six six seven seven eight eight.
If we go here, we are switching the Miry Appendix II, which is at index zero here 11, I would replace
11 with my great length.
It is here it is eight and eight minus.
I are equal to zero at minus one, so 11 replaced by eight eight.
Now I need to.
Replace here we have them equal to 11 at the first iteration.
OK, so temp is a stored.
R11 is stored in temp equal 11.
OK, now.
11.
We have eight, eight have been successfully switched, but eight eight still here we have here my array
at the end at length minus I, which is zero at the first iteration and minus one, which is here.
So it's it's like indicating that eight eight part or element equal to temp.
So assign a temp equal 11, so replace eight eight by 11.
So the first, the switching is done as this and so on.
And the second iteration, temporary equal temp, equals my array at index one.
And next one is equal to so temporary is equal to.
OK, now we have add my array at Index I at index one is equal to my array.
That length is eight minus I index a one minus one.
So it is 77.
So replaced 22 by 77.
My array at index here what we have switched and taken.
The result is equal to tempt.
So go and get the temp and replace it again and so on.
Tell switching all the elements tell that half of this array.
OK, so we should replace all the half of the first of the first half of.